Elijah Palmer

Chickasha, OK | palmermelijah@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/elijah-palmer | github.com/ElijahMPalmer

OBJECTIVE: Software Engineering Position

Maintenance Supervisor with 4 years of Honorable military service. B.S. in Software Engineering (33 Credit Hours Completed), 2+ Years of practical experience working with Software Development, Certification and experience with Mechanical and Architectural drafting, experience in training, collaboration, developing curriculum and supporting organization maintenance, modifications, and administration.

Coaching / Mentoring
Counseling / Evaluations

Inspection / Safety
Java / JavaScript / HTML / CSS /
SQL

Critical Thinking / Analysis Public Speaking / Delegation

PROJECTS

Arithmetic Sequence Calculator, Java

GitHub: https://github.com/ElijahMPalmer/Kalkutron-9001-Basic-Calculator-

Core Technologies: Java, Swing Framework, AWT Framework

Summary: Java Swing GUI application that allows a user to type in any arithmetic sequence and the program will return the solution. (ex. (1+2) / (3*6)) The GUI features a clear, evaluate, and exit function. The program first breaks each character of the inputted String into tokens and stores them all in a Queue data structure. Next it uses two stack data structures (Operand and Operator stack) to filter through the Queue, completing portions of the sequence by following the order of operations through pushing and popping stack elements then producing the solution. This project provided experience with stack and queue data structures, using node elements, AWT framework, and foundational operations of Java Programming.

Pixel Art Maker, JavaScript

GitHub: https://github.com/ElijahMPalmer/pixel-art-maker **Core Technologies:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript and the DOM API

Summary: Web App that allows a user to choose from a set of preset colors or a color picker to "paint" a canvas of pixels. This app allows the user to not only click on an individual pixel to paint it but also click and drag to act as a paint brush. The Canvas was created with HTML and Javascript (To repeat the pixels a chosen number of times to create the canvas). The rest of the application was styled with CSS and functionality was added with JavaScript Event Listener and using the DOM API to manipulate elements dynamically.

Car Wiz Vehicle Resource Hub

URL: https://github.com/ElijahMPalmer/Car-Wiz

Core Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, DOM API, FullPageJS FrameWork, JQuery, and 3rd Party API to parse data.

Summary: Web App that allows a user to enter the VIN of their vehicles to find out basic information such as engine type and horsepower as well as resources to find Owners manuals and maintenance forums for their make of vehicle. The application used HTML, CSS, DOM API, and FullPageJS Framework for styling and formatting of the website. JQuery and the 3RD Party API are used to decode the User's VIN and store the results to be used on the page. This project improved my knowledge on API usage and manipulating DOM elements based on an APIs response. This project is a work in progress and is actively being updated on GitHub.

EDUCATION | CERTIFICATIONS | LICENSE | TRAINING

Elijah Palmer

B.S. Software Engineering, Arizona State University (33 Credit Hours Completed), Tempe, AZ Galvanize Full Stack Software Engineering BootCamp (Graduate June 3, 2022), Oceanside CA Drafting Technician Certification (24-month resident course), Canadian Valley Technology Center, Chickasha, OK Intermediate Additive Manufacturing Certification (40-hour resident course) U.S. Marine Corps, Oceanside, CA Basic Additive Manufacturing Certification (40-hour resident course), U.S. Marine Corps, Oceanside, CA Innovation Bootcamp Certificate of Completion (40-hour resident course), U.S. Marine Corps, Oceanside, CA Intermediate Leadership (80-hour resident course), U.S. Marine Corps, Oceanside, CA Intermediate Maintenance Course (16-week resident course), U.S. Marine Corps, Oceanside, CA Basic Repairers Course (12-week resident course), U.S. Marine Corps, Oceanside, CA Marine Combat Training (4-week resident course), U.S. Marine Corps, Oceanside, CA Basic Military Training (13-week resident course), U.S. Marine Corps, San Diego, CA

EXPERIENCE

Modifications Supervisor, 3rd AABN, U.S. Marine Corps, Oceanside, CA (02/2021-06/2022)

Led 5 Diesel Technicians working 8 hour shifts daily consisting of verifying and completing safety and functionality related modifications to vehicles, supporting 1,000+ cross-functional 3rd Assault Amphibian Battalion (3rd AABN) staff representing 4 reporting departments and \$1B+ in rolling and electronic equipment, while maintaining operational readiness and safety via managing training, supervision and administration.

- Qualified technicians to install/ verify equipment modifications, by training students on installation tasks/ methods through on-the-job training and direct supervision daily
- Improved organization's readiness from 80% to 99% in 9 months by identifying and addressing individual department's specific remedies for modification completion and verification status
- Increased local repair capability and reduced Modification project costs per unit from \$2K+ to \$2, by identifying alternate local manufacturing methods to obtain back ordered parts
- Maintained work status log according to organizational standards, by recording time, material and labor demands via web based Global Combat Support System and Windows PC daily

Preventative Maintenance Supervisor, 3rd AABN, U.S. Marine Corps, Oceanside, CA (03/2020-02/2021) Managed 5 Diesel Technicians working 8 hour shifts daily consisting of Semi-annual preventative maintenance, checks and services, supporting 1,000+ cross-functional 3rd Assault Amphibian Battalion (3rd AABN) staff and 225+ fleet vehicles [\$456 M+] in preservation of equipment and safety by managing supervision, training, administration and scheduling.

- Tested and qualified technicians to conduct preventative maintenance, by training students on tasks/ procedures through on-the-job training and direct supervision daily
- Facilitated Preventative Maintenance Quality Control program by inspecting job completion and documentation compliance with organizational standards daily
- Maintained scheduled worklog according to organizational standards, by recording time, material and labor demands via web based Global Combat Support System and Windows PC daily

Additive Manufacturing Instructor, 1st MEF, U.S. Marine Corps, Oceanside, CA (08/2019- 03/2020)
Assisted instructor reporting to 2 supervisors working 8 hour shifts in a 900 sqft. classroom environment while providing Engineering course work and facilitation for 53,000+ 1st Marine Expeditionary Forces (1st MEF)

cross-functional staff by facilitating a bi-weekly 40 hour basic/ intermediate Additive Manufacturing course consisting of lectures, PowerPoint presentations and practical application for 8+ students covering Computer Aided Drafting,

Elijah Palmer

Reverse Engineering and 3D Printing aiding in organization repair capability and lead time by managing instruction, curriculum development, maintenance and training analysis.

- Taught 16+ students 3D printing, Computer Aided Drafting and reverse engineering skills monthly, by developing lesson plans and instructional materials and practical skills evaluations
- Supported Explosive Ordnance Disposal (EOD) staff's specific operational demands by developing custom course curriculum in 30 days: 40-hour basic/ intermediate Additive Manufacturing class, by combining curriculum and developing projects relative to organization's specialized field/ industry standards
- Developed Training Analysis Program consisting of monthly meetings and soliciting comments/ criticism from graduates for stakeholder review and planning
- Maintained Training center's accommodation of 16 Students by servicing and repairing 16 3D printers weekly
- Evaluated and qualified 2 instructors and supervisor to oversee and train students in a classroom setting through walkthrough/ practical application instructional methods

Diesel Technician, 3rd AABN, U.S. Marine Corps, Oceanside, CA (04/2019-08/2019)

Assisted 4 technicians reporting to 2 supervisors, working 8 hour shifts daily consisting of troubleshooting, operating diagnostic test equipment and malfunction repair, while supporting 1,000+ cross-functional 3rd Assault Amphibian Battalion staff and 225+ fleet vehicles in operation readiness by managing maintenance and preventative maintenance.

- Maintained vehicle readiness to organizational standard by troubleshooting, repairing and replacing worn or broken components
- Ensured vehicles were operating in compliance with organizational standards by using diagnostic test equipment in accordance with training procedures daily
- Supported weekly training and deployment operations by conducting semi-annual preventative maintenance consisting of vehicle operation/ safety inspection in accordance with organizational standards daily

Volunteer/ Community Experience

Techlahoma Community Member

State-Wide (Oklahoma) volunteer-run nonprofit that empowers community members by equipping them with life-enriching skills.